Vikram Shishupalsingh Bais

+91 8412917566 Portfolio Website vikrambais02@gmail.com Linkedin GitHub CodeChef CodeForces

Objective:

The opportunity for that will allow me to advance my experience and all my technical and nontechnical skills in an organization where I could contribute my solid background in programming. My endeavor and dedication in the internship will be helpful in achieving the company's goals and objectives.

Education:

| Course | Institution | Year of passing | Grade |
|---|--|-----------------|----------|
| B.tech (Computer Science and Engineering) | Guru Ghasidas Vishwavidyalaya | 2022(Pursuing) | 8.5 cgpa |
| HSC | Progressive Junior Science College, Gondia(MH) | 2018 | 88.15 % |
| SSC | Gujarati National High School, Gondia(MH) | 2016 | 89.98 % |

Technical Skills:

Programming Languages (Proficient): Python, C++, C

Programming Languages (Familiar) : Java, Assembly language

Topics (Proficient) : OpenCV, Data Structures, Problem solving, Machine Learning

Topics (Familiar) : HTML, CSS, Deep Learning, Neural Networks

Database : Mysql

Tools : Git and Github, Gerrit, Arudino, Docker

• OS : Linux(Ubuntu), Windows

Experiences:

Algorithm and Data Structure Developer, Intern (OPENGENUS, May 2021-present):

Writing Technical articles, Working on development tasks regarding DSA

Competitive Programming Club Lead (Developer Student Clubs - GGV, Bilaspur | Oct 2020 - present):
Develop logical and problem solving skills, Organize workshops, Competitions related to Competitive Coding.

Tech. Event Coordinator (GIRLSCRIPT-Chapter Bilaspur | June 2020 - present):

Conduct Technical events, Organize workshops for awareness about Technology.

• Open Source Contributor:

<u>Libreoffice</u> - free and open-source office productivity software suite (Jan 2021-present) : (6+ PR merged)

Hacktoberfest 2020 - Fest organized by digital ocean: (3 PR merged)

Data Science and Analytics intern (The Sparks Foundation | Sept 2020 - Oct 2020):

Completed tasks that include exploring algorithms, creating ML models.

• Graphic Designer (EQUILIBRIO 2k20(Techfest) | Dec 2019 - present):

Create Graphics and Illustrations for Techfest.

Achievements:

- 3 Star coder (Codechef)
- Participated in Cisco_ISTE_National_CODATHON-2020 organized by cisco
- Winner of Code Debug event at EQUILIBRIO 2020 (techfest organized by School of Studies and Engineering And Technology Guru Ghasidas Vishwavidyalaya)

Projects:

Augmented Reality (Tools: OpenCV, Python, Aruco Marker) (Project link):

Project detects aruco marker, predicts its orientation and then shows a 3d object or 2d image over the Aruco marker.

Cat vs Dog Image Classifier (Tools: CNN, Tensorflow, Keras, Python) (Project link):
Project uses CNN to classify images of Cat and Dog.

• Credit Card Fraud Detection (Tools: Sklearn, Python, Machine Learning) (Project link):

Model trained in kaggle data set using python and sklearn library.

• Basic calculator (Tools: .Net Framework, C#) (Project link):

Calculator for basic calculation(+,-,/,*,%).

Interests: Technology enthusiast, Cyber gaming, Solving puzzles, Sketching